(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN
WELCOME TO HOSHIMACHI SUISEI
for YouTube Live
私がここにいることを、この世界に知らしめる
I will let the world know that I am here.
SPACE for Virtual GHOST
震えている 闇を穿って
Piercing through the trembling darkness
その中の 淀みを打て
Strike the stagnation within it
計算と保守
Calculation and conservation
自分勝手なルール
Selfish rules
歪んでる事実
Distorted facts
期待を消去して
Erase all expectations
向かうべき未来の目摘んでいる
Plucking the buds of the future we should head for
正体 探し出して
Find your true identity
その手を掴んで
Grab that hand
光の射す明日へ
And head for a tomorrow where light shines
影も連れて
Taking your shadow along
きっと 冷たくてバイバイ
Surely it's cold, so bye-bye
雨だって 誰か救っているから
Because even the rain is saving someone
平行線を繋げば輪になる
If you connect parallel lines, they form a circle
光に変えて
Turn it into light
音を立てて ズレていく世界
A world that goes out of sync with a sound
SOSの群れ 僕を消耗して
The crowds of SOS wear me out
近すぎてぼやけた
It was too close and became blurred
現実と未来
Reality and the future
まだ手を伸ばせる
I can still reach out my hand
正体を探して
Searching for your true identity
向かうべき未来の目
The buds of the future we should head for
その中 耳をすましてみれば
If I try to listen closely within that
ドミノ世界に 光を祈って待っている
Waiting and praying for light in a domino world
窓の外 抱いて
Embrace it outside the window
きっと いつか疲れて
Surely, even if I get tired someday
全てを消してしまいたくなっても
and want to erase everything
君の声が 僕を呼び戻す
Your voice will call me back
Umma...
よく見て　痣の傷
Look closely at these bruises and wounds,
少し変われば　晴れる
if they change even a little, it will clear up.
矢印の方へ　それが示す明日へ
Towards the arrow, towards the tomorrow it points to.
ふらついたって行ける　きっと
Even if I stumble, I can go, I'm sure of it.
歪な世界の　その先
Beyond this distorted world,
小さな光がある
there is a small light.
すべてが叶う　楽園じゃなくても
Even if it's not a paradise where everything comes true,
君がここにいる風は
the wind that tells me you're here
そっと　僕の背中を押している
is gently pushing me forward.
平行線の先を　繋いだなら
If we connect the ends of the parallel lines,
光の輪になれ
then become a ring of light.
出航！　LOVE! THUNDER GLOW
Setting sail! LOVE! THUNDER GLOW
LOVE! THUNDER GLOW
OH YEAH　LOVE! THUNDER GLOW
OH YEAH LOVE! THUNDER GLOW
螺旋を描き　揺れてるデザイア
Drawing a spiral, a swaying desire.
居心地が良いのが　鏡の世界のまやかし
What feels comfortable is the deception of the mirror world.
火花にげ　壊れることを恐れていた
The sparks fled, I was afraid of breaking.
そう　どうか線を隠してた
Yes, I was hiding the lines somehow.
ビリビリ震えてる　水面（みなも）夢をあふれさせる
The water's surface is trembling, making dreams overflow.
勝ち気が必要
A strong-willed spirit is needed.
シグナル伝えてる　非常事態
Sending signals, an emergency situation.
堕天使になるなんて　嘘みたいだね
Becoming a fallen angel, it's like a lie, isn't it?
双子の宇宙　似ていない自分が
Twin universes, a self that doesn't resemble.
備え欠けてた　パズルを合わせたら驚ける
If I put together the puzzle that lacked preparation, I'll be surprised.
重荷はずして　優しいフリでごまかしていた
Taking off the burden, I was deceiving with a kind pretense.
でも　くちづけさえ忘れてた
But I even forgot the kiss.
めりめり熱くなる　肌を空を破り進む
Becoming red-hot, tearing through skin and sky as I move forward.
ハートは火薬で
My heart is gunpowder.
その時きいている　ハラを割って稲妻走る
Hearing it at that moment, speaking frankly, lightning strikes.
震え感じたら
If you feel the vibration,
乾いたいたずら　錆び付く強がりを
a dry prank for the rusted bluff.
ダイブな視線で　ナイフに変えよう
With a diving gaze, let's turn it into a knife.
無表情崩して
Break that expressionless face.
忘れていた　鍵を回すから
Because I'm turning the key I had forgotten.
ビリビリ震えてる　水面（みなも）夢を...
The water's surface is trembling, making dreams...
夢を溢れさせる
Making dreams overflow
カチキが必要
A competitive spirit is needed
シグナル伝えてる
I'm sending a signal
非常事態
An emergency
堕天使になるなんて御免被りたいわ
Becoming a fallen angel? No thank you!
メリメリ熱くなる
Getting hotter and hotter
果てを空を破り進む
Breaking through the end of the sky, I move forward
ハートは火薬ね
My heart is gunpowder
その時来ている
That time has come
殻を破って
Break through the shell
稲妻走る震え感じたら
If you feel the tremor of lightning running
ジャズル
Jazzle
抱きしめるよ
I'll embrace you
馬鹿げてるね過去
The past is so ridiculous
溢れたら
If it overflows
ジャズル
Jazzle
はい！
Yes!
ということで、皆さん聴いてくれてありがとうございました！
So, everyone, thank you for listening!
彗星の如く現れたスターの原石、アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいです！
A shooting star that appeared like a comet, the idol VTuber, Hoshimachi Suisei!
すいちゃわ～！今日も可愛い！
Sui-chan is~! Cute today as well!
ということでちょっとね、お水を飲ませていただきますよ。
So, I'm going to drink some water.
これ、これはみんなに見えない水。
This, this is water you guys can't see.
はい。
Yes.
ということでですね、星街すいせい、3月22日で、あの3周年を迎えました！
So, I, Hoshimachi Suisei, reached my 3rd anniversary on March 22nd!
あとね、誕生日も3月22だったんですけども。
Also, my birthday was also March 22nd.
今日はね、その3周年を記念して、あと生誕祭もやって、
Today, to celebrate that 3rd anniversary and also have a birthday festival,
あの大盤振る舞いでライブをこの日にね、やらせていただこうと思います！
I'm going to put on a lavish live performance today!
はい。えっとですね、
Yes. Um,
こちらにタグが出てますので、たくさん呟いてください。
The tag is shown over here, so please tweet a lot.
ハッシュタグ #星街すいせい3周年LIVE
Hashtag #星街すいせい3周年LIVE
あのね、世界トレンド1位になりたい。お願いします！
You know, I want to reach number one on the world trends. Please!
はい、ということでね、今回セトリ詰め詰めにしてしまったので、MCの時間があんまりないらしいです！
So, because I packed the setlist this time, it seems there isn't much time for MC!
ということで、次の曲いっていきたいと思います！いっていきたい、いきたいと思います。
So, I want to move on to the next song! I want to, I want to move on.
次はなんと、あの人が！
Next, surprisingly, that person!
ゲストとして来てくれます。
Will be coming as a guest.
それでは次の曲いきましょう！
Then, let's go to the next song!
朝を迎えに行こう
Let's go greet the morning
眠い目を擦って
Rubbing our sleepy eyes
今日を生き抜こう
Let's live through today
ということでにじさんじから戌亥とこちゃんが来てくれました！
So, Inui Toko-chan from Nijisanji has come!
まいど！
Hello!
うぇ～い！
Yay!
おめでとうさん！
Congratulations!
ありがとう～！
Thank you~!
悲しまないで
Don't be sad
迷いそうなら
If you feel like getting lost
大きく息を吸って
Take a deep breath
Baby いつ終わらないで
Baby, please don't let it ever end
自分を忘れそうなら
If you feel like you're losing yourself
そんな奴とは離れなよ
Just walk away from people like that
って言いたいだけだけど 愛なら
I just want to say that, but if it's love,
分け合えるはずだから
We should be able to share it
頑張って頑張って作り上げたものが
Something we worked hard, worked hard to build
簡単に簡単に壊れても
Even if it breaks easily, breaks easily
増えていく朝でいたいな
I want to be in a morning where things increase
笑える人と出逢いたいな
I want to meet people who can laugh
でありたいな
I want to be that way
Baby 着飾らないで
Baby, don't dress up
ありのままが素敵だって
That being as you are is wonderful
知ってるかい
Do you know?
Baby 激しい雨も
Baby, even the heavy rain
気が付きゃ晴れていることが
If you notice it, it's clearing up
殆どだ
Most of the time
楽しいことが少ないから
Because there are few fun things
批判的になんだろう
I guess I'll get critical
傷ついて傷ついて隠す力は
The power to get hurt, get hurt and hide it
あー 大切な...
Ah~ the precious...
...大切な方へと
...to the precious one.
おー
Oh~
もうこんなところで泣くすなよ
Hey, don't cry in a place like this.
Don't cry in a place like this.
誰もわかっちゃいないわけでもない
It's not like nobody understands.
広く深い夜なら そろそろ褪せちゃいそう
In the wide and deep night, it seems about to fade away soon.
一人でさまようには 寂しさが邪魔をする
Loneliness gets in the way of wandering alone.
君だけを 見ていたい
I want to look only at you.
光は遠くだけど
The light is far away, but...
ライ、ライ
Lie, lie
でも
But...
頑張って 頑張って 作り続けてみよう
Let's keep working hard and keep on creating.
大切な 大切な方へと
To the precious, precious one.
こんなところで泣くすなよ
Don't cry in a place like this.
笑える朝を迎えに行こうかいま
Shall we go to meet the morning when we can laugh, right now?
イェーイ
Yeah!
はい！ということで！
Alright! And with that!
おっしゃー！
Alright!
改めまして、にじさんじから戌亥とこちゃん来てくれました！
Once again, Inui Toko-chan from Nijisanji has joined us!
まいどー！戌亥とこです！
Hello~! I'm Inui Toko!
イェーイ！まいど！
Yay! Hello!
はい、ということで、あの、とこちゃんは、
Yes, and so, um, Toko-chan...
えー、去年12月、ソロライブをやりまして。
...held a solo live last December.
そうなんです、やらせていただきました。
That's right, I was able to do that.
その時にですね、ゲストで私を呼んでくださったんですよ。
At that time, she invited me as a guest.
来ていただきました。
You came for me.
そうなんです。一緒に歌ったり踊ったりね、頑張ったんですけども、
That's right. We worked hard together, singing and dancing...
まぁ、それがあったので、私も自分のライブにとこちゃん呼びたいなと思いまして、
...so because of that, I wanted to invite Toko-chan to my own live as well...
呼び返しました！
...and so I've invited her back!
呼ばれ返しました！
I've been invited back!
呼ばれ返しました。
I've been invited back.
めっちゃ秘密にしてたからたぶん、みんな気づいてなかった。
We kept it very secret, so I think everyone didn't realize.
そうだね。
That's true.
だって、今日とこちゃんのツイートでさ、「あ、今日やん。みんな見よな」
I mean, in Toko-chan's tweet today, you said, "Oh, it's today. Everyone watch it."
「嘘つけお前！もうおるやんけ！」みたいな。
Like, "Liar! You're already there!"
しらじらしー、しらじらしいなと思いまして。
I thought, "How shameless! So shameless!"
えーとですね、ということで、次の曲歌ってとこちゃんとはお別れになります。
And so, after singing the next song, it will be time to part ways with Toko-chan.
またね、みんな。
See you later, everyone.
早い早い！
Too fast!
またね！
See you!
はい、お次に歌う曲は、
Yes, the next song we'll sing is...
ヨルシカさんの曲になります。
...a song by Yorushika.
ちょっと切なげなね、曲ですので、
It's a slightly bittersweet song, so...
切なげな曲でお別れしたいと思います。
...I'd like to part ways with a bittersweet song.
はい。
Yes.
見送る気あるんかな、みたいな。
"Does she even want to see me off?"
それでは聴いてください。
Please listen.
「盗作」。
"Plagiarism".
音楽のきっかけは何だっけ。父の持つレコードだったかな。
What was my inspiration for music? Was it the records my father owned?
音を聞くことは気持ちが良い。聞くだけなら努力もいらない。
Listening to sounds feels good. Just listening requires no effort.
前置きはいいから話そう。
Skip the preamble, let's talk.
ある時、思い付いたんだ。
One day, I thought of it.
この歌が僕の物になれば、この穴は埋まるだろうか。
If this song became mine, would this hole be filled?
だから 僕は盗んだ
That's why I stole it.
ああ、まだ足りない 全部足りない
Ah, it's still not enough, it's all not enough.
何一つも満たされない
Not a single thing is satisfied.
このまま一人じゃ僕は生きられない
I can't live like this alone.
もっと知りたい 愛を知りたい
I want to know more, I want to know love.
この心を充たすくらい
Enough to fill this heart.
美しいものを知りたい。
I want to know beautiful things.
ある時に、街を流れる歌が
One day, a song playing in the streets...
僕の曲だってことに気が付いた。
...I realized it was my song.
売れたなんて当たり前さ
It's only natural it became a hit...
名作を盗んだものだからさ！
...because it's a stolen masterpiece!
彼女も馬鹿だ。こいつも馬鹿だ。
She's a fool. He's a fool.
褒めちぎる奴等は皆馬鹿だ。
Those who praise it are all fools.
群がる五の衆 本当の価値なんて分からずに。
A swarming crowd, without knowing its true value.
「あぁ、それは僕も同じか」
"Ah, I guess I'm the same."
「僕も同じふり」
"I also pretend the same"
何かが足りない
Something is missing
これで完成したのに
Even though it's finished
少しも満たされない
I'm not satisfied at all
上っ面の言葉一つじゃ満たされない
A single superficial word won't satisfy me
愛が知りたい
I want to know love
金が足りない
I don't have enough money
この妬みを満たすくらい
Enough to satisfy this envy
美しいものを知りたい
I want to know beautiful things
「音楽のきっかけが何なのか」
"What was the catalyst for my music?"
今じゃもう忘れちまったが
I've already forgotten by now, but...
欲じゃないことは覚えてる。
I remember that it wasn't greed.
何か綺麗なものだったな。
It was something beautiful.
化けの皮なんていつか剥がれる。
The mask will eventually peel off.
見向きもされない夜が来る。
A night where no one looks my way will come.
その時に見られる景色が 心底楽しみで
I'm truly looking forward to the scenery I'll see then
そうだ
That's right
何一つ無くなって
Everything disappears
地位も名誉も全部無くなって
Status and honor, all gone
何もかも失った後に見える夜は本当に綺麗だろうから
Because the night seen after losing everything will surely be beautiful
本当に
Truly
本当に綺麗だろうから
Because it will surely be beautiful
僕は盗んだ
I stole it
ああ、まだ足りない
Ah, it's still not enough
もっと描きたい
I want to draw more
こんな歌じゃ満たされない
A song like this won't satisfy me
君らの罵倒じゃ僕は満たされない
Your insults won't satisfy me
まだ知らない
I still don't know it
愛を描きたい
I want to draw love
この心を満たすくらい
Enough to satisfy this heart
美しいものを知りたい
I want to know beautiful things
まだ足りない まだ足りない まだ足りない まだ足りない
Still not enough. Still not enough. Still not enough. Still not enough.
まだ足りない 僕は足りない
Still not enough. I'm not enough.
ずっと足りないものが分からない
I still don't know what's missing
まだ足りない もっと知りたい
Still not enough. I want to know more.
この身体を溶かすくらい
Enough to melt this body
美しい夜を知りたい。
I want to know the beautiful night.
つまんない
Dull
コンクリート
concrete
ビエラ
Viera
君は歩く
You walk
作詞・作曲・編曲：n-buna
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: n-buna
僕は一歩 後ろから
I follow a step behind
たなびく 青の薄
Trailing blue pampas grass
邪魔で仕方ないと笑った
You laughed, saying they were in the way
君はもういない
You're no longer here
瓦礫から 仲間外れ
An outcast from the rubble
石ころ 蹴飛ばして 踏みつけて 知らんぷり
Kicking a pebble, stepping on it, pretending not to notice
君は前だけを見ていた
You were looking only ahead
僕は君だけを 見ている
I am looking only at you
朝焼けと 夕焼けの色彩を
The colors of sunrise and sunset
青空と 水溜りの色彩を
The colors of the blue sky and puddles
仕方ないな 吹き飛ばした
It can't be helped. I blew them away.
昨日見た夢と
The dream I saw yesterday and...
今日をいつわった空想を
The fantasy that feigned today
ノートに書いた落書き
Doodles in a notebook
君は明日へ歩いてた
You were walking towards tomorrow
つまんない コンクリート
Dull concrete
僕はここで立ち止まったまま
I remain standing still right here
...な 名の花に
...to the flowers with a name
名前をつけて呼んだ
I gave them a name and called out to them
からかう君はもういない
You, who teased me, are no longer here
光るレンズから 仲間外れ
Left out from the shining lens
寂しいアルバムは ポケット 皺くちゃ
The lonely album in my pocket is all wrinkled
君は前だけを見ていて
You were looking only forward
僕は君だけを見ている
I'm looking only at you
降り注ぐ太陽の隙間を
Through the gaps of the pouring sun
星空と暁の隙間を
Through the gaps between the starry sky and the dawn
仕方ないなと諦めずに
Without giving up and saying "it can't be helped"
産むことの叶わない形と願っていた
I wished for a form that couldn't be born
君は気づいてる
You've realized it
遡ってもう終わらない
Going back, it will never end
僕の髪を撫でた君は
You, who stroked my hair
君の歌を掴んだ僕は
I, who grabbed your song
僕の耳に触れた君は
You, who touched my ear
君の背中にしがみついた僕は
I, who clung to your back
あの時一番暖かかった僕らは
We, who were the warmest back then
もういない
Are no longer here
HOLOBAND
結成
Formation
vocal&base * 星街すいせい
vocal&base * Hoshimachi Suisei
guitar * 常闇トワ
guitar * Tokoyami Towa
keyboard * 夏色まつり
keyboard * Natsuiro Matsuri
drums * アキ・ローゼンタール
drums * Aki Rosenthal
DJ * 尾丸ポルカ
DJ * Omaru Polka
Wow...
LET'S PARTY
SHOUT OUT
Wow...
LET'S BARK
世界トレンド1位ありがとうございます！
Thank you for the #1 worldwide trending!
星街すいせい3周年ライブ、まだまだ盛り上がっていけー！ホロライブー！
Hoshimachi Suisei's 3rd Anniversary Live!
Keep the energy up, Hololive!
Don't wait 何も成さないまま
Don't wait, without achieving anything
勝った気になって さぁ 準備して Such a fool
Thinking you've won, now get ready, such a fool
まだまだ終わらせない
It's not over yet
Show me now Fasting path ぶっ壊して 叫べ
Show me now, break that fasting path and shout
腹から Sing along 爆上げ Here we go
Sing along from your gut, let's go crazy!
Everyday Everynight 中途半端に生きるな
Every day, every night, don't live half-heartedly
灰になるまで いっそな事 Everything
Until you turn to ash, give it your everything
燃え尽きてみろよ Understand?
Burn yourself out, understand?
アハハ！愉快痛快 限界に煽れ
Ahaha! Delightful and thrilling, push to the limit
自分自身を あちこち そっちまで Evolution
Take yourself here, there, and everywhere, Evolution!
お後がよろしいようで
That's it for me, folks!
Shout! Never say never crazy Come on crazy night
ほら Crazy 味わい尽くせ
Look, it's crazy, savor it all
哀しみも人生さ
Even sorrow is part of life
Never say never crazy Come on crazy night
ほら Crazy Oh make some noise
Look, it's crazy, oh make some noise!
Wait... いつか止むのはいつなの？
Wait... when is the day it finally stops?
言い訳 Nonsense ダラダラ乗っかってるな
Excuses are nonsense, don't just go with the flow
飛び出せ Limit さっさと駆け抜けて
Break the limit, run through it quickly
本音で Sing along 爆上げ Here we go
Sing along with your true feelings, let's go crazy!
Everyday Everynight 目に写る 弱虫
Every day, every night, the coward in your eyes
蹴り飛ばして 常識ごと 頭ひっくり返せよ Understand?
Kick them away, flip your common sense upside down!
Understand?
オーライ 縦横無尽 自由自在の 自己主張
Alright, running wild and free with self-assertion
グッとウルサイ 際まで 今すぐ Showdown
Loud as can be, right to the edge, showdown now!
意義はお有りですか？ Shout!
Any objections? Shout!
Never say never crazy Come on crazy night
ほら Crazy 自分らしくしろ
Look, it's crazy, just be yourself
邪魔する奴らは Boo!
Boo to those who get in the way!
Never say never crazy Come on crazy night
ほら Crazy Oh make some noise
Look, it's crazy, oh make some noise!
世界を包み出すのは
What begins to envelop the world
お前の本気の産声だけ
is only your first true cry
一瞬きりなら 後悔せず生き抜け
If it's only for a moment, live it without regret
Never say never crazy Come on crazy night
ほら Crazy 味わい尽くせ
Look, it's crazy, savor it all
哀しみも人生さ
Even sorrow is part of life
Never say never crazy Come on crazy night
ほら Crazy Oh make some noise
Look, it's crazy, oh make some noise!
みんな、ありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
えー、なんと、ホロライブバンド、結成しましたー！
Well, believe it or not,
we've formed a Hololive band!
それが私たち、「AIARS（アイアーズ）」！
And we are "AIARS"!
なんでAIARSなんだい！？
Why AIARS?!
はい、AIARS結成しましたが、なんと、
Yes, we formed AIARS, but...
次の曲で、解散となりまーす！
we're disbanding after the next song!
えーーー！？今聞いたばっかりだよ！？早すぎるよ！
What?! We just heard about it!
That's way too fast!
はい、ということで、最後の曲聴いてください。EXPOSE 'Burn out!!!'
Alright, so please listen to our last song.
EXPOSE 'Burn out!!!'
いっくよー！
Here we go!
盛り上がっていけー！
Let's get hyped!
頭、頭振って飛ばせー！ぶっ飛べー！
Headbang, keep those heads moving!
Let's blow it away!
EXPOSE 'Burn out!!!'
心 ぶちかます
Strike your heart hard
舌をなめずり
Licking your lips
暗い呪文 並べて
Lining up dark spells
Any more?
笑顔で 今日をサボ
Skipping today with a smile
Come down 嗜めて
Come down, reproving them
仮面を使い分けて やってる
Switching between masks, I do it
Show time!
笑わす? 涙を? 楽しんだもん 勝ち
Making them laugh? Or cry? Whoever enjoys it wins
NO! NO!
マジやってんの? お決まりですの?
Are you serious? Is it a routine?
Me? 罪? Attention Let's ぶち壊して
Me? Sin? Attention! Let's smash it all
Countdown 3 2 1 乗りこなせ
Countdown 3 2 1, ride it well
EXPOSE 'Burn out!!!'
回せ 回せ 何もかも 今すぐ さらけ出せ
Spin it, spin it, everything, expose it all right now
Everybody 獣みたく 叫べよ
Everybody, howl like a beast
You can change the world
僕たちの歌で
With our song
Welcome to us
Let me go Let it show Let me go
Get your gun! Let's shoot! Bang! Bang!
魑魅魍魎 打ち砕け
Smash the evil spirits
Get your gun! Let's shoot! Bang! Bang!
偽善者たちを バイバイ
Bye-bye to the hypocrites
口を開けば 吹き出す モヤモヤ 不平不満 掃き溜め
Every time I open my mouth, out comes a cesspool of hazy discontent
生い茂り 育てていたんだ
It was growing thick, I was nurturing it
Do you know? いつの間に 火花が踊り出し はしゃぐ
Do you know? Before I knew it, sparks began to dance and frolic
Show time!
Hey! Hi! お得意の言い訳 並べて 今ね 大事?
Hey! Hi! Line up your usual excuses, is it important now?
NO! NO!
よく履きなよ こちらも飽きちゃいな
Wear them well, I'm getting tired of this too
Me? 罪? Attention 舞になりな Any
Me? Sin? Attention! Become a dance, any...
Countdown 3 2 1 止まらない
Countdown 3 2 1, it won't stop
EXPOSE 'Burn out!!!'
回せ 回せ 何もかも 今すぐ 解き放て
Spin it, spin it, everything, unleash it all right now
Everybody 獣みたく 正直に
Everybody, be honest like a beast
You can change the world
僕たちの歌で
With our song
Welcome to us
星街すいせい3周年ライブ、まだまだいくぞー！
Hoshimachi Suisei's 3rd anniversary live, we're just getting started!
頭振れー！
Headbang!
己の意味 差し示せよ
Show the meaning of yourself
I say, You say, We say
Me? 罪? Attention 快進撃の途中
Me? Sin? Attention! In the middle of an onslaught
Countdown 3 2 1 乗りこなせ
Countdown 3 2 1, ride it well
EXPOSE 'Burn out!!!'
回せ 回せ 何もかも 今すぐ さらけ出せ
Spin it, spin it, everything, expose it all right now
Everybody 獣みたく 正直に
Everybody, be honest like a beast
You can change the world
EXPOSE 'Burn out!!!'
回せ 回せ 何もかも 今すぐ さらけ出せ
Spin it, spin it, everything, expose it all right now
Everybody 獣みたく 叫べよ
Everybody, howl like a beast
You can change the world
僕たちの歌で
With our song
Welcome to us
Let me go Let it show Let me go
Get your gun! Let's shoot! Bang! Bang!
魑魅魍魎 打ち砕け
Smash the evil spirits
Get your gun! Let's shoot! Bang! Bang!
偽善者たちを バイバイ
Bye-bye to the hypocrites
Don't run away!
hololive production
Welcome to Hoshimachi Suisei's 3rd YouTube Live
SPACE FOR VIRTUAL GHOST
Welcome, Welcome, Welcome, Welcome to Virtual GHOST!
Dancing in the moonlight
一度きりの人生の 一秒も 後悔したくない 絶対
I don't want to regret even a single second of my one and only life, absolutely.
見えない明日に 描き出す希望を 諦めたくないよ 行くよ Look at me
I don't want to give up on the hope I draw for an unseen tomorrow, let's go, Look at me.
Everybody's alright
恥ずかしがらないで 常識は捨てて 右の頬に Kiss me now
Don't be shy, throw away common sense, Kiss me now on my right cheek.
Dancing in the moonlight 聞かせてあげる Music
Dancing in the moonlight, I'll let you hear the music.
気が済むまで踊り出せ いつだって 一緒だよ 覚悟しててね
Dance until you're satisfied, we're always together, be prepared.
Dancing in the moonlight この光 It's the night
Dancing in the moonlight, this light, It's the night.
星なく輝いて どこまでも 歌声は 響いてくのずっと
Shining like a star, forever and ever, my singing voice will keep echoing.
みんなお待たせしました！
Everyone, sorry to keep you waiting!
Dancing in the moonlight
今日も月の下で 待ち合わせ でも準備が全然 終わんないよ
Meeting under the moon again today, but I'm not finished getting ready at all.
会いたい すぐに会いたい 焦る気持ちを しずめなきゃ
I want to see you, I want to see you right away, I have to calm my racing heart.
歌う準備 歌は愛 歌は希望 よし これで大丈夫
Ready to sing, song is love, song is hope, alright, this is okay.
Everybody let's go!
眠れない夜に サヨナラ
Goodbye to the sleepless nights.
Dancing in the moonlight
夢まで届く Don't you imagine
Reaching all the way to your dreams, Don't you imagine.
I just only love
後ろの方まで全部見えてるよ！ありがとう！
I can see all the way to the back! Thank you!
Dancing in the moonlight
星空連れてって 銀河の果てまで 止まらないで Don't stop Don't stop
Take me to the starry sky, to the edge of the galaxy, don't stop, Don't stop Don't stop.
ぶつけた想い君に 熱い想い全部 代わらないよ Oh my darling
The feelings I struck you with, all my hot feelings, won't change, Oh my darling.
一回 Call my name
Just once, call my name
Call my name
Feel on me baby
このリズムに乗って あの星掴めば
Ride this rhythm, and if I catch that star
いつもよりも Wonderful
It'll be more wonderful than ever
Wow wow Wonderful
Dancing in the moonlight
月の光 感じて
Feel the moonlight
Dancing in the moonlight
このリズム 止められない
I can't stop this rhythm
Dancing in the moonlight
聴かせてあげる Music
I'll let you hear the music
銀河中 踊り出せ
Dance throughout the galaxy
いつだって一緒だよ
We're always together
覚悟しててね
Get ready
Dancing in the moonlight
この光 Enjoy
Enjoy this light
眩しく輝いて どこまでも歌声は
Shining brightly, my singing voice will...
響いていくの ずっと
...echo forever
Dancing in the moonlight
みんな！ペンライト振ってー！
Everyone! Wave your penlights!
少年ブレイブ
Shonen Brave
いじめないでねって祈った手ばかり
Just hands that prayed "Don't bully me"
震えちゃうのも仕方ないんです
It's no wonder they're trembling
孤独を何より恐れてる
Afraid of loneliness more than anything
少年の僕を「勇気」は嫌った
Courage hated the boy me
同じように雨に濡れてる
Getting wet in the rain just the same
子犬に理解を求めてた
Seeking understanding from a puppy
自分勝手に引き寄せてた
Selfishly drawing it close
「君は僕をいじめないよね」って言って
Saying "You won't bully me, right?"
友達になろう 言葉じゃないところでさ
Let's be friends, in a way that's not words
話がしたいような そんな僕に悲劇が待ってた
A tragedy was waiting for me, who wanted to talk
聞こえたんだ 声が盛大に
I heard a voice, loudly
拒絶した脳をノックする
Knocking on my rejected brain
「あいつは汚い」「こいつを騙そう」
"That guy is dirty," "Let's trick this guy"
「大嫌い」「死んじゃえよ」なんて
"I hate you," "Just die," and so on
思いの声が一斉に
Voices of thoughts all at once
拒んでいたってノックする
Knocking even though I refused
言葉にしない心が突き刺さってもう泣きそう
Wordless hearts pierce through, I'm about to cry
「希望を願った」バサバサって
"I hoped for hope," with a flutter
僕ものぞこう
I'll peek too
僕にこんな代償を植え込んでた
Planted such a price in me
そして今日も声が溢れ立てる
And today too, voices are overflowing
流れ込んで僕を汚して
Flowing in and tainting me
人の「真理」を盗み取れる
Can steal people's truths
異常な僕を誰もが嫌った
Everyone hated the abnormal me
「逃げ出そう」と外へ飛び出せ
Jump outside to run away
ここじゃもう息もできないから
Because I can't even breathe here anymore
街の雑踏 目を避けてさ
The city's bustle, avoiding eyes
僕はそっと駆け出した 土砂降りの中
I quietly started running in the downpour
迷い込む森 行き場のない静けさに
Wandering into a forest, in a silence with nowhere to go
また怯えちゃうような そんな僕を誰かが待ってた
Someone was waiting for me, who was about to be scared again
聞こえたんだ 今日も淡々と
I heard it today too, indifferently
描いた今日を待ってるの
Waiting for the today I drew
「誰かお願い ここから助け出してよ」
"Someone please, save me from here"
「寂しいよ」なんて 思いの声は純真な
Voices of thoughts like "I'm lonely" are innocent
昨日の僕のようだった
Were just like me yesterday
挨拶した
I said hello,
物語の全貌で
to the full picture of the story.
僕はそっと慎重に描いてた
I was gently and carefully drawing it out.
行き詰まった症状は言った
The symptoms of reaching a dead end said,
昨日も今日も一昨日も
yesterday, today, and the day before yesterday too.
この世界が簡単に崩れちゃう夢を見てた
I had a dream that this world would easily crumble away.
怖いようなんて感情も
Even emotions like "I'm scared,"
辛いようなんて泣き声だって
and even cries like "It's so painful,"
絵本みたいに救い出してしまえたなら
if only I could rescue them like in a picture book.
芽生えた今日の感情を
The feelings that sprouted today,
絞った声でノックして
I'll knock with a squeezed-out voice,
君に話そう それでも「大丈夫だよ」って
and talk to you; let's still laugh together
笑い合って
and say "It's okay."
思いの声の心臓を 包んで
If we could wrap up the heart of these
笑い合えたなら
yearning voices and laugh together,
心を救う 心を救う 勇気と呼べた
I could call it the courage to save the heart.
進み始めた毎日そう
Every day that's started to move forward, yes,
君は今日も平凡で
you are ordinary today too,
ドアの外の声はもう聞こえない
and the voices outside the door are no longer heard.
プロミスザスター / 作詞：JXSKK 作曲：松隈ケンタ 編曲：SCRAMBLES
Promised Star / Lyrics: JXSKK Composition: Kenta Matsukuma Arrangement: SCRAMBLES
どのくらい
How much...
歩いてきたんだろう
...have I walked, I wonder?
怯えて過ごす毎日だった
It was a daily life spent in fear.
勘違い わがまま 一太刀
Misunderstanding, selfishness, a single stroke...
僕らを引き裂いていた
...was tearing us apart.
散々眺めた
I gazed endlessly...
夢の続きが
...at the continuation of a dream.
そうさ 傷跡に塩を塗り込んでいく
That's right, it keeps rubbing salt into the wounds.
だから僕は待って 待って 未来を待って
So I wait, wait, wait for the future.
立って ずっと生きてるって感じてたかったから
I wanted to stand and feel that I'm alive forever.
だから君を待って 待って 未来を待って
So I wait for you, wait, wait for the future.
待って きっと巡り合った僕らは奇跡なんだ
Wait, surely we who met by chance are a miracle.
どれだけ話せばわかってくれる
How much do I have to talk for you to understand?
Don't you see Everytime あの空を染めてけ
Don't you see, Everytime, go dye that sky.
プロミスザスター
Promised Star
どれくらい立ち止まっただろう
How much did I come to a standstill, I wonder?
怯えて過ごす毎日だった
It was a daily life spent in fear.
迷っては戻る 過去たちが
Getting lost and returning, the pasts...
僕らを追い越してく
...are overtaking us.
散々眺めた
I gazed endlessly...
夢の続きが
...at the continuation of a dream.
そうさ 茜さす日々を照らしていく
That's right, it illuminates the madder-red days.
変わらない想いを持っていられたら
If I could keep my unchanging feelings...
いいな だってずっとこれだけって思ってきたんだから
...that would be nice, because I've always thought this was all.
だから君を待って 待って 未来を待って
So I wait for you, wait, wait for the future.
待って 絶対約束されたものなんかないんだ
Wait, there's absolutely no such thing as a promise.
答えは神様だけが知ってる
Only God knows the answer.
Don't you see Everytime あの空を染めてけ
Don't you see, Everytime, go dye that sky.
…ずっと 最後の誓いを果たすまで
...Forever, until I fulfill the final vow.
だから僕を待って 待って 未来を待って
So wait for me, wait, wait for the future.
立って ずっと生きてるって感じてたかったから
Standing, because I wanted to feel alive forever.
だから君を待って 待って 未来を待って
So wait for you, wait, wait for the future.
待って きっと巡り会った僕らは奇跡なんだ
Wait, surely we who met are a miracle.
どれだけ離せば分かってくれる？
How far apart must we be for you to understand?
Don't you see everytime 瞳閉じて
Don't you see everytime, close your eyes.
Don't you see everytime あの空を染めていけ
Don't you see everytime, go dye that sky.
プロミスザスター！
Promise the Star!
いやー、えー、皆さん、えー、お疲れ様です。
Phew... uh, everyone... uh, good work.
お水を飲ませてください。
Please let me drink some water.
あー、えー、すいません途中でなんか、あのー、
Ah... uh, sorry, in the middle, some...
機材トラブルが起こって、
...equipment trouble occurred,
あのー、配信における全ての機材が、あの、シャットアウトするという…
and, uh, all the equipment for the stream, uh, shut out...
マジでびっくりした、本当に。すいません。
I was really surprised, seriously. I'm sorry.
それでも見てくれてるみんな、本当にありがとうございます！
But to everyone who is still watching, thank you so much!
ちょっと10時過ぎてしまったんですが、あ、そ、そ、そうだ。あのー、これ凄くない？
It's past 10 PM now, but... oh, right. Uh... isn't this amazing?
ゴンドラ！私が運営さんに我儘言って付けてもらいました。
A gondola! I was selfish and asked the staff to put it in for me.
ゴンドラ凄いでしょ？みんなのことも、もう、みんな見えてる、みんな見えてる。ありがとう！
The gondola is great, right? I can see everyone, I can see all of you. Thank you!
はい。ということで、えー、次は、まだ歌うんです。
Yes. So, uh, next... I'm still singing.
なんと、まだ歌うんです。
Surprisingly, I'm still singing.
次は、えー、オリジナル曲を歌っていきたいと思います。
Next, uh, I'd like to sing an original song.
えっと、このライブ限定のスペシャルバージョンになっていますので、
Um, it's a special version exclusive to this live,
ぜひ、ぜひ、最後まで、最後まで見ていってください。よろしくお願いします！
so please, please, watch until the very, very end. Thank you!
それではいきましょう！
Alright, let's go!
あの空で輝いた 流れ星を追いかけて
Chasing the shooting star that sparkled in that sky
いつか君を照らすから 彗星のスターライト
Because I'll shine on you someday, a comet's starlight
彗星のスターライト
Comet's Starlight
Comet
生まれたばかりの小さな光は
A small light that was just born
消えてしまいそうな声で歌を歌ったんだ
Sang a song with a voice that seemed like it would vanish
誰かに届くように その声を振り絞って
Squeezing out that voice so it reaches someone
今はまだ響かなくても いつかその心に
Even if it doesn't resonate now, someday in that heart
明ける今夜は眠れないほどに胸躍らせて
Dawning tonight, my heart is dancing so much I can't sleep
私のこと見ていてね 彗星のスターライト
Keep watching me, okay? A comet's starlight
画面の前の、お前らー！
You guys in front of the screen!
天球、彗星は夜を跨いで
Tenkyu, Suisei wa Yoru wo Mataide
まだまだ終われない！最後まで、盛り上がって、行けるよなー！
We're not done yet! You're ready to stay hyped until the end, right?!
明かりが一つ灯った 灯った 天を彩った 描が綺麗で
A light turned on, it turned on. The drawing that colored the heavens was beautiful
天球、彗星は夜を跨いで
Tenkyu, Suisei wa Yoru wo Mataide
...だ
...da
僕の吐いた白い息のように 消してしまえたらな
If only I could erase it like the white breath I exhaled.
押し殺して深く沈んだ 泣き声さえ響いているから
Because even the suppressed, deeply sunken sobs are echoing.
君を刺した不安も苦痛も 僕の青色で塗りつぶして
Let me paint over the anxiety and pain that pierced you with my blue.
全部、涙になって 星の海を辿っていった
Everything turned into tears and traced the sea of stars.
果てしない闇の中に そっと手を添えたらほら
If I gently place my hand in the endless darkness, look...
彗星が僕の頭上を飛んだ
A comet flew over my head.
誰もいない夜の空を埋めた
Filling the empty night sky.
深くに沈まった街の中へ 降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう
Whose sadness is raining down into the deeply sunken city?
星はまた雲抜けて飛んだ
The star flew through the clouds again.
靄のかかった思考を晴らして
Clearing away the misty thoughts.
いつかまた会えるなんて言えなかった
I couldn't say that we'd meet again someday.
星が降ったあとの街 僕はもうずっと君の行方を探してた
In the city after the stars fell, I've been searching for your whereabouts all this time.
もし今、頷いて目を見ている 描かれたその時を待ってるの
If now, I'm nodding and looking into your eyes, am I waiting for that moment to be drawn?
きらめく空 決めてる日々に 伝える、このメロディ
To the days decided by the sparkling sky, I'll convey this melody.
わー！3周年、本当にありがとう！
Wow! Thank you so much for the 3rd anniversary!
みんなも一緒に歌ってください！
Everyone, please sing along too!
4年目もいくぞー！
Let's go for the 4th year too!
窓から覗いた 雨の降る街並みを
I peered through the window at the rainy city streets.
弾ける音だから ポケットに詰め込んで
Because it's a popping sound, I'll stuff it in my pocket.
Let's dance now 君の好きな キャラメルのステップに乗せて
Let's dance now, to the beat of your favorite caramel steps.
魔法のような ライムライトが私を照らしてる
Like magic, the limelight is shining on me.
星を繋いで 夢を描くよ
Connecting the stars, I'll draw my dreams.
描かれたその声が呼んでるの
That voice that was drawn is calling out.
きらめく空 待ってた君に 届ける このメロディ
To the sparkling sky and you who were waiting, I'll deliver this melody.
このままじゃね 終われない
I can't let it end like this.
Special & Stage 踊り明かすの
Special & Stage, we'll dance all night.
このままじっとしてられない
I can't just stand still like this.
走り出そうよ 世界は変わるから
Let's start running, because the world will change.
歌って！
Sing!
La la la...
明日は晴れるから
Because tomorrow will be clear.
La la la...
明日は晴れるから
Because tomorrow will be clear.
浅く弾けた感情に
In the shallowly popped emotions.
言い訳を並べて過ごした
I spent my time lining up excuses.
勝ちも知らない街灯に
To the streetlights that don't even know victory.
君だけだって嘘を見た
I saw the lie that it was only you.
信じたくもないままで 踊っている
Dancing without even wanting to believe.
指の隙間に連ね続けた
I continued to string them together through the gaps in my fingers.
言葉 見えないの 僕が
Words... I can't see them.
僕の この声が聞こえてる
My... can you hear this voice of mine?
Dancer in the dark シルエット すらも 肯定できた
Dancer in the dark, I could even affirm the silhouette.
...っ不恰好だけれど でも
...I'm unrefined, but still...
全て声を枯らそう
I'll sing until my voice gives out
必死に縋っても ずっと正面を射抜くわ
Even if I desperately cling to it, I'll keep piercing right through
ねえ ゴーストみたいだ
Hey, I'm like a ghost
散々恨んだ当たり前と
I've resented the "ordinary" countless times
アンバランスに伸びてゆく影
An unbalanced shadow stretching out
散々遠すぎた一滴の
A single drop that was far too distant
君の言葉で泣きたくなった
Your words made me want to cry
大切にしたいものが零れてゆく
The things I want to cherish are spilling away
示すままに綴り続けたい言葉
Words I want to keep writing as they come
見えてるの 僕が
Can you see me?
僕の声が聞こえてる
Can you hear my voice?
Dancer in the dark
シルエットすらも透明できっと
Surely even my silhouette is transparent
不恰好だけれど でも
I'm unrefined, but still...
だから叫んで抗って
So I'll scream and struggle
裸足のまま走って
Running barefoot
ねえ 気付いて教えてよ
Hey, notice me and tell me
答えは
The answer is
こんな僕の心まで馬鹿にしないで
Don't make a fool of my heart like this
灰色の街が嗤ってる
The gray city is sneering
足取りも重くなる
My steps are becoming heavy
声を枯らして叫んで抗って
Screaming until my voice is gone, struggling
裸足で走り続けて
Keeping on running barefoot
変わらないように諦めないように
So that I don't change, so that I don't give up
連ね綴るだけだ
I just keep on composing
見つけてよ 僕を
Find me
僕の声が聞こえてる
Can you hear my voice?
Dancer in the dark
シルエットすらも透明できっと
Surely even my silhouette is transparent
不恰好だけれど でも
I'm unrefined, but still...
全て声を枯らそう
I'll sing until my voice gives out
必死に縋っても
Even if I desperately cling to it
ずっと正面を射抜くわ
I'll keep piercing right through
ねえ ゴーストみたいだ
Hey, I'm like a ghost
新曲「GHOST」ミュージックビデオ
The music video for my new song "GHOST"
このあとすぐプレミア公開！
Will have its premiere right after this!
星街すいせい 3周年記念グッズ
Hoshimachi Suisei 3rd Anniversary commemorative goods
このあと0時から販売開始！
Will go on sale at midnight tonight!
買ってね！
Please buy them!
4th YOUTUBE LIVE
SPACE for Virtual GHOST
何千回何万回
Thousands, tens of thousands of times
繰り返したって
No matter how many times I repeat it
この声は届かないまま
This voice remains unheard
消えていくんだな
I guess it's just going to fade away
幽霊みたいだ
Just like a ghost
GHOST